citizensvoice.com 2015-12-19

# Times-Shamrock Communications Online Privacy & Posting Policies

**Privacy Policy | Hatchback Policy | Opinion Posting Policy | About our ads **

**  
** Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of Times-Shamrock Web sites, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement(the"Statement") discloses the privacy practices for Times-Shamrock Web sites (the "Website") - what information we gather, how we use it and how to correct or change it. This Statement only addresses our activities from our servers. Other sites (including those to which the Web site links and third party sites providing services to Times-Shamrock Web sites) may have their own privacy policies and practices, which we do not control. Questions regarding this Statement should be e-mailed to [contactus@timesshamrock.com](mailto:contactus@timesshamrock.com).

_ General Privacy Information_

Times-Shamrock's network of sites contain links to partners, advertisers and third party Internet sites and services who may collect data in connection with sweepstakes, promotions, e-commerce, etc. They each have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of Times-Shamrock Web sites and Times-Shamrock Web sites have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily and publicly disclose personal information on any online service or Web site- for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Further, while we strive to protect your personal information, Times-Shamrock Web sites cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

**Use of Information**

All of the information Times-Shamrock Web sites collect, both what you tell us and what we collect through the use of cookies, is "aggregated" - meaning that the information from many users is grouped together in a way that does not disclose the personal information of any particular user. We may use this aggregated information to evaluate which products and services are successful and which are not, and in order to evaluate which new services we should make available on our Web site. We may use only the anonymous click stream data to help our advertisers deliver better-targeted advertisements. Times-Shamrock Web sites will not disclose any information about any individual without the individual's consent, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process. There may be some cases in which some of your personal information may be used by Times-Shamrock Web sites to target e-commerce promotions and telemarketing activities. In addition, it may be shared with Third Parties who assist Times-Shamrock Web sites in producing its Web sites or provide a service to Times-Shamrock Web sites' users.

Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this Statement, the practices of Times-Shamrock Web sites with respect to personal information or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact [The Times-Shamrock Interactive Media Department](mailto:contactus@timesshamrock.com), or write to:

Interactive Media  
Times-Shamrock Web sites  
Attn: Privacy Statement  
149 Penn Avenue  
Scranton, PA 18503  
**Fax** : 570-504-8201

Third Parties

Legacy.com [Terms of Use](http://www.legacy.com/ns/termsofuse.aspx) and [Privacy Policy](http://www.legacy.com/ns/PrivacyPolicy.aspx)

Times-Shamrock websites use the services of third-party network advertisers on its site. Network advertisers are third parties that attempt to show customized advertisements based on visits to this Website and unrelated Web sites of others by your computer or web browser. Click on links below for information about these companies [including any choices on participation in their service].

**Registration**

Anyone who participates in interactive activities (chat, message boards or opinion posting, contests, store and product purchase, membership program, classifieds) on Times-Shamrock's network of Web sites may be asked to register for a free guest ID and password or to complete subscription registration for a member ID and password. We use customer contact information from this registration form to send the user information about our company and promotional material from some of our partners. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary for customer service reasons. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings; please reference your Personal Options. Unique identifier such as ID and passwords, are collected to verify the user's identity and for use as account numbers in our record system.

**Children Under the Age of 13**

We do not currently collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. Under certain circumstances, visitors may be asked to submit a screen name as a means of identifying communications to Times-Shamrock Web sites  
Children of any age should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online.

If in the future, Times-Shamrock Web sites collect personally identifiable information from children, it will do so in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.).

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user that has no meaning outside the assigning site. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. This random number lets us keep track of "how many" times customers are doing specific things - like visiting our site each month - without really knowing who those customers are. We also use cookies to keep track of your shopping cart and to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your member ID. Additionally, after you've entered your member ID and password during a session on our service, we save that information so you don't have to reenter it repeatedly during that session.

Users shouldbe aware that Times-Shamrock Web sites cannot control the use of cookies or the resulting information by advertisers or third parties hosting data for Times-Shamrock Web sites. If a user does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the user to deny or accept the cookie feature; however, users should note that cookies may be necessary to provide the user with certain features (e.g., customized delivery of information available on the Times-Shamrock network of Web sites).

**Surveys**

Our online surveys ask visitors for their e-mail address and demographic information. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitors experience at our site, showing them content and promotional offers that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. This information is shared with advertisers only on an aggregate basis. We may use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company and promotional material from Times-Shamrock websites or some of our partners. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings in Personal Options.

**Contests**

We run contests on our sites in which we ask visitors for Times-Shamrock Web sites ID and password. We use contact data from our contests to send users information about upcoming contests and promotional offers. On occasion we will e-mail customers promotional material from some of our partners. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary for winner notification and prize delivery confirmation. The majority of the contests that we offer are hosted on Times-Shamrock sites; however, there may be cases in which a third party sponsor will host the contest and collect user information. In those cases, we urge users to review the privacy statement of the third party site. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings in Personal Options.

**Changes**

Times-Shamrock Web sites reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy without notice. In the event of a change of this policy, procedures will be developed for users to opt-out or otherwise prohibit any future use of their individually identifiable information that is not currently covered under this policy.

**_ABOUT OUR ADS_**

Times-Shamrock Communications participates in the APT from Yahoo! platform and Yahoo! is an ad network partner to display ads on our sites. To improve your ad experience on Times-Shamrock Communication sites and elsewhere on the Internet, we may send non-personal information to Yahoo! based on your browser’s activities, such as type of pages viewed and categories of interests, so that the advertising you see is relevant to you. Yahoo! also may use information regarding its own users to select which ads to display. [Learn more](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html) about Yahoo!’s ad practices, including how to opt out of using anonymous information to select which ads to show you. Yahoo! is a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

_ OPINION POSTING POLICY  
_Updated:  4-22-09 Times Shamrock Communications Posting & Opinions policy

By entering any opinion, posting or other user generated content you are agreeing to be bound by these conditions and terms. Please read carefully!

Any individual posting a message, music file, recording of any kind, photo, video or opinion in a public guest book, forum, opinion posting area or any other area is the sole author of and is exclusively and entirely responsible for the opinions and statements in the posted message. Times Shamrock and its affiliates disclaim all responsibility for the content of such messages, postings, community generated content and are acting merely as an impartial conduit for constitutionally protected free speech and as a provider of an interactive computer service.

While the administrators and moderators of this user generated content or postings will attempt to remove any generally objectionable material as quickly as possible, it is impossible to review every message. Therefore you acknowledge that all posts made to these forums, opinions posted and user generated content express the views and opinions of the author and not the administrators, moderators, Scranton Times LLP or its affiliates and parent company or companies or webmaster and hence will not be held liable.

You agree not to post, email, or otherwise make available Content:

that is unlawful, harmful, threatening, abusive, harassing, defamatory, pornographic, libelous, or invasive of another's privacy, or harms minors in any way;   
that harasses, degrades, intimidates or is hateful toward an individual or group of individuals on the basis of religion, gender, sexual orientation, race, ethnicity, age, or disability;   
that purports to be from any person or entity, including but not limited to a Provider employee, or falsely states or otherwise misrepresents your affiliation with a person or entity;   
that includes personal or identifying information about another person without that person's explicit consent.   
that is false, deceptive, misleading, deceitful, mis-informative, or constitutes "bait and switch";   
that infringes any patent, trademark, trade secret, copyright or other proprietary rights of any party, or Content that you do not have a right to make available under any law or under contractual or fiduciary relationships.   
that advertises any illegal services or the sale of any items the sale of which is prohibited or restricted by applicable law, including without limitation items the sale of which is prohibited or regulated by law   
that contains software viruses or any other computer code, files or programs designed to interrupt, destroy or limit the functionality of any computer software or hardware or telecommunications equipment;   
that disrupts the normal flow of dialogue with an excessive number of messages (flooding attack) to the Service, or that otherwise negatively affects other users' ability to use the Service; or   
that employs misleading email addresses, or forged headers or otherwise manipulated identifiers in order to disguise the origin of Content transmitted through the Service.   
Additionally, you agree not to:   
contact anyone who has asked not to be contacted;   
"stalk" or otherwise harass anyone;   
collect personal data about other users for commercial or unlawful purposes; use automated means, including scripts, spiders, robots, crawlers, data mining tools, or the like to download data from or upload data to the Service;   
post irrelevant Content, repeatedly post the same or similar Content or otherwise impose an unreasonable or disproportionately large load on our infrastructure;   
attempt to gain unauthorized access to Provider’s computer systems or any other user's computer systems, or engage in any activity that disrupts, diminishes the quality of, interferes with the performance of, or impairs the functionality of, the Service

Doing so may lead to you being immediately and permanently banned (and your service provider being informed). You agree that the webmaster, administrator and moderators of this forum have the right to remove, move or close any topic at any time should they see fit. As a user you agree to any information you have entered above being stored in a database. While this information will not be disclosed to any third party without your consent the webmaster, administrator and moderators cannot be held responsible for any hacking attempt that may lead to the data being compromised.

This system may uses cookies to store information on your local computer. These cookies do not contain any of the information you have entered above; they serve only to improve your viewing pleasure. If an e-mail address collected it is used only for confirming your registration details and password.

Under no circumstances will Scranton Times LLP or its affiliates and parent company, Times-Shamrock Communications, be liable in any way for any content or for any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of the use of any content posted in any forum or opinion posting area, or otherwise made available on the site. You acknowledge that Provider shall have the right (but not the obligation) in its sole discretion to refuse, delete or move any Content that is available via the Site, for violating the letter or spirit of the Terms or for any other reason. Scranton Times LLP or its affiliates and parent company, Times-Shamrock Communications reserves the right to delete any posting, message or photograph at any time, for any reason or no reason.

By entering any opinion, posting or other user generated content you are agreeing to be bound by these conditions and terms.

 This policy explains the privacy practices of Times-Shamrock Communications and Hatchback LLC (“Hatchback”), (Collectively referred to as “the Companies”), with respect to the Hatchback platform (the "Application") and any use of the Application (Collectively referred to as "the Services"). It describes the ways the Companies collect and use your personal information and the rights and options available to you.

This policy is incorporated into the Companies’  _Terms of Use_  (the "Terms of Use" or the "Terms").

By surfing, logging or connecting to, accessing or using the Services, you acknowledge that the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy constitute a binding and enforceable legal contract the Companies and you, or any person connecting to, accessing or using the Services.

The Services are not intended for use by persons under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years old, you may not download or use the Applications with the Services turned on, you may not use any feature of the Website or Services that requires registration and you may not provide us with any of your personal details. The Companies will not knowingly collect any personal information of persons under 13 years old. In this policy, the term 'personal information' means any information that may be used with reasonable efforts to identify you, such as a first and last name, home address, phone number and email addresses.

 Contact the Companies / Abuse reports

If you believe that your privacy has been compromised by any person, in the course of using the Services, please contact contactus@timesshamrock.com. You may send the Companies other requests, responses, questions and complaints by contacting contactsus@timesshamrock.com.

 Personal information that you provide

When you register with the Services, you may be asked to provide certain contact and personal details, such as mobile device number and e-mail address. False, incorrect, or outdated information may impair our ability to provide you with the Services and to contact you when necessary. You may create your personal profile on the Services. Your profile will be available to other users and will include information that does not personally identify you, such as your gender, age, city and state. Further information, such as your Hatchback rank, Hatchback points amount, nickname, avatar, driving distance, check-in locations, driving time, trips taken may be used and shared with other users, when you use the Application. Further information may be collected when we exchange communications with you, for example, if you submit a request, contact our support team, or report a violation to the abuse team.

 Personal information that you share

The Services are based on users' locations, time spent travelling, stops made, distances travelled, trips taken and submissions that may include certain personal information. The content is not private or confidential, and you should not have any expectation of privacy with respect to it. You must exercise caution and common sense when posting information that may personally identify you or others. At the very least, you should demonstrate the same degree of caution as when publishing personal information by means other than the Internet and cellular services. The content that you post may be available to other users of the Service and to MANSI. Some of the content that you share, for example in a forum feed or blog post on the Website, may be viewed by all Internet users.

 Location based information that we collect

When you use your mobile device with a copy of the Application installed, the Companies collect your location information. We use that information to provide you and other users with the Services. We may make further use of your location information by providing you information about sites, shops and other places and attractions in your vicinity. We may also use your location information to create aggregated anonymous data and to use such data in accordance with this policy (please refer to use of aggregated information chapter hereunder). The Companies will make commercially reasonable efforts to remove or obscure your identity from your location information that is used for aggregated purposes.

 Opting out of location information services by uninstalling the Application

At all times you may uninstall the Application, by using the Application's uninstall option, or by using the programs removal feature of your operating system. Following the uninstallation process, we will not be able to collect any further location based information from you, or provide you with location based information about sites, shops and other places and attractions in your vicinity.

 Meta-data that we collect

The Companies collect information about the use of the Services. For example, we may record the frequency and scope of your use of the Services, the duration of your sessions, the web pages that you visit, information that you read, content that you use or create, advertisements that you view or click on, your communications with other users and third parties, the mobile identifier that serves access to the Services, and the geographic location of the device that you are using to log-in. 

 What do the Companies do with your personally identifiable information?

The Companies may use your personally identifiable information for the following purposes:

·         to provide the Services and to enable you to use the Services. For example, we may use the phone number that you provide to send you updates and other recommendations, and to send you a text message containing a link to download the Application and to provide you with your preliminary username and password;

·         to operate the Services and to improve and customize your experience with the Services, as well as the experience of other users;

·         to provide you with support and handle request and complaints;

·         to send you updates, notices, announcements, and additional information related to the Services;

·         to send you rewards or prizes related to locations you frequent;

·         to send you marketing and advertising material through your mobile device, e-mail messages, social media, or other such mediums, subject to your prior indication of consent. At any time you may opt out of the Services' mailing lists, by changing your preferences in your personal account or by sending a written notice to: contactsus@timesshamrock.com;

·         to conduct surveys and questionnaires;

·         to share your submissions with other users of the Services and to facilitate communication between you, Hatchback, Times-Shamrock and other users;

·         to enforce the Terms of Use;

·         to contact you when we believe it to be necessary;

·         to comply with any applicable law and assist law enforcement agencies under any applicable law, when Hatchback or Times-Shamrock has a good faith belief that cooperation with the law enforcement agencies is legally mandated or meets the applicable legal standards;

·         to prevent fraud, misappropriation, infringements, identity theft and other illegal activities and misuse of the Services;

·         To handle breakdowns and malfunctions;

·         to take any action in any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and the Service, or between you and other users or third parties with respect to, or in relation with the Service;

·         For purposes provided under this policy and the Terms of Use.

Sharing information with others

Except as provided herein, the Companies do not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties. The Companies will not share your personally identifiable information with others, without your consent, except for the following purposes and to the extent necessary in the Companies’ good-faith discretion:

·         When you use the Services, when you take part in content-related activities and when it is necessary to facilitate the functionality of the Services.;

·         If Hatchback or Times-Shamrock reasonably believes that you have breached the Terms of Use, or abused your rights to use the Services, or performed any act or omission that Hatchback or MANSI reasonably believes to be violating any applicable law, rules, or regulations. Hatchback and Times-Shamrock may share your information in these cases, with law enforcement agencies and other competent authorities and with any third party as may be required to handle any result of your wrongdoing;

·         If Hatchback or Times-Shamrock is required, or reasonably believes that it is required by law to share or disclose your information;

·         In any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and Hatchback or Times-Shamrock, or between you and other users with respect to, or in relation with the Services;

·         In any case where Hatchback or Times-Shamrock reasonably believes that sharing information is necessary to prevent imminent physical damage or damage to property;

·         If Hatchback or Times-Shamrock organizes the operation of the Services within a different framework, or through another legal structure or entity, or if Hatchback or MANSI is acquired by, or merged into or with another entity, or if Hatchback or Times-Shamrock enters bankruptcy, provided however, that those entities agree to be bound by the provisions of this policy, with respective changes taken into consideration;

·         Hatchback or Times-Shamrock may also share personally identifiable information with companies or organizations connected, or affiliated with Hatchback or Times-Shamrock, such as subsidiaries, sister-companies and parent companies, and other partners, with the express provision that their use of such information must comply with this policy.

Accessing your personal information

At any time you may access your account on the Services and edit, or amend your personal information. If you find that the information on your account is not accurate, complete or updated, than you must make all necessary changes to correct it. Please keep in mind that false, incorrect, or outdated information may prevent you from registering with the Services and impair the ability to provide you with Services.

How do the Companies use aggregated information?

The Companies may use or sell anonymous, statistical or aggregated information to properly operate the Services, to improve the quality of the Services, to enhance your experience, to create new services and features, including customized services, to change or cancel existing content or service, and for further internal, commercial and statistical purposes. The Companies may also use anonymous, statistical or aggregated information collected on the Services, by posting, disseminating, transmitting or otherwise communicating or making available such information to users of the Services, to the Services' providers, partners and any other third party.

Data retention

The Companies may retain location information longer than required to provide the Services and for reasonable business needs. 

The Companies may at all times review, retain and disclose any other information as either deems necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request and Hatchback's or Times-Shamrock’s needs and necessities. By doing so, neither Hatchback nor Times-Shamrock expressly or impliedly endorse, affirm or in any manner assume any responsibility for such communications.

Cookies

The Companies may use cookies on the Services. Cookies are packets of information sent by a Website's servers to your web browser and then sent back by the browser each time it accesses the Website's servers. The cookies may contain a variety of information, such as the content of search queries, the Website's pages you have accessed, session durations and IP addresses. The Companies may use cookies for various purposes, such as to save you the need to re-enter your username and password each time you log-in, to facilitate the use of a Website, to collect statistical information, to verify information, and to customize a Website to your personal preferences and for information security purposes. Some of the cookies may expire when the session ends and you exit your browser. Other cookies are saved on your computer’s hard drive. If you wish to block a Website's cookies, then please use the help button in your browser and follow the necessary instructions. However, bear in mind that disabling cookies may complicate or even prevent your use of a Website, or certain features thereof.

Advertising campaigns

The Companies may permit, solicit or contract certain other companies to conduct advertising campaigns on the Services. The advertisements that you see when accessing the Services are redirected from the servers of those advertising companies and may be geographically or contextually targeted. Some advertisers may use cookies on your computer in combination with geo-targeted data collected from your mobile device. The cookies enable them to collect information about sections and features that you have accessed, advertisements posted on those sites and the advertisements that you have viewed. In this manner advertisers try to customize advertisements to your preferences and for their own business purposes. The advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies and not to this Policy. If you wish to study the privacy policies of those advertisers you should visit their services, or contact them directly.

Information Security

The Companies consider information security to be a top priority. Although we make reasonable efforts to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee and you cannot reasonably expect that the databases will be immune from any wrongdoings, malfunctions, unlawful interceptions or access, or other kinds of abuse and misuse.

 Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Companies may from time to time change the terms of this policy. Substantial changes may take effect immediately after Hatchback or Times-Shamrock has posted an initial notification on the Website's homepage or mobile apps it is embedded in, with respect to such changes. Other changes may also take effect immediately after their initial posting on the Website, unless Hatchback  or Times-Shamrock amends this policy to comply with legal requirements. In such cases the amendments will also become effective immediately upon their initial posting, or as required. You agree to be bound by any of the changes made in the terms of this policy. Continuing to use the Services will indicate your acceptance of the amended terms. If you do not agree with any of the amended terms, you must avoid any further use of the Services.

Last modified: June 10, 2014

_**Times-Shamrock Communications Web Sites:**_
